const question = [{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'What is the smallest prime number ?',
  Option: ['0', '1', '2', '3'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which of the following is a composite number?',
  Option: ['11', '13', '9', '7'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'What is the value of the digit 5 in the number 8,549?',
  Option: ['5', '50', '500', '5000'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which Roman numeral represents the number 100?',
  Option: ['C', 'D', 'X', 'M'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 5,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'What is the sum of the first three prime numbers?',
  Option: ['6', '10', '11', '15'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 6,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'What is the product of 7 and 8?',
  Option: ['14', '56', '64', '15'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 7,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Which of the following is an odd number?',
  Option: ['20', '31', '42', '50'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 8,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'What is the place value of the digit 9 in the number 4,987?',
  Option: ['9', '90', '900', '9,000'],
  rightAns: 2
}, {
  queid: 9,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Which of the following is a multiple of 5?',
  Option: ['12', '15', '18', '21'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 10,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'If a number ends in 0, what is it always divisible by?',
  Option: ['2', '5', '10', '100'],
  rightAns: 2
},
// Chapter 2 - Basic Arithmetic
{
  queid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'What is the result of 58 + 37?',
  Option: ['85', '955', '105', '115'],
  rightAns: 0
}, {
  queid: 2,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'What is the product of 6 and 9?',
  Option: ['45', '54', ' 63', '72'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 3,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'If a rectangle has a length of 12 units and a width of 8 units, what is its area?',
  Option: ['80 square units', '96 square units', '100 square units', '120 square units'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 4,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'What is the difference between 87 and 56?',
  Option: ['21', '31', '41', '51'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 5,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'What is the quotient of 63 divided by 9?',
  Option: ['6', '7', '8', '9'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 6,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'What is the sum of the first ten natural numbers?',
  Option: ['45', '55', '65', '75'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 7,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'What is the value of 4 in the number 948?',
  Option: ['4', '4000', '400', '40'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 8,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Which of the following is a prime number?',
  Option: ['12', '17', '20', '25'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 9,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'If you multiply a number by 0, what is the result?',
  Option: ['0', '1', 'The original number', 'It\'s not possible to multiply by 0'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 10,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 2,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'What is the value of 7 in the number 372?',
  Option: ['70', '7', '700', '7000'],
  rightAns: 1
},
// Chapter 3 : Fractions and Decimals
{
  queid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'What is the decimal equivalent of the fraction 3/4 ?',
  Option: ['0.25', '0.5', '0.75', '1.25'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 2,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which of the following is the smallest fraction?',
  Option: ['3/5', '4/5', '2/3', '5/8'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 3,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Which of the following is the smallest fraction?',
  Option: ['3/5', '4/5', '2/3', '5/8'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 4,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'What is the result of 2/3 + 1/6 ?',
  Option: ['3/6', '1/2', '5/6', '7/6'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 5,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'If you multiply a fraction by 1, what is the effect on the fraction?',
  Option: ['It becomes zero.', 'It remains the same.', 'It becomes the reciprocal.', 'It doubles'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 6,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'What is the decimal equivalent of 5/8?',
  Option: ['0.4', '0.5', '0.625', '0.75'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 7,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'If you divide 3/4 by 1/2, what is the result?',
  Option: ['3/8', '2/3', '4/3', '5/6'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 8,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Which of the following is a proper fraction?',
  Option: ['5/3', '3/2', '4/4', '2/7'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 9,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'If you subtract 1/3 from 4/5, what is the result?',
  Option: ['5/15', '1/15', '3/5', '1/2'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 10,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 3,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'What is the fraction equivalent of the decimal 0.2?',
  Option: ['1/5', '1/10', '2/10', '2/5'],
  rightAns: 0
},
// chapter 4 - Measurement
{
  queid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'What is the standard unit for measuring length in the metric system?',
  Option: ['Feet', 'Inches', 'Centimeters', 'Yards'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 2,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'How many millimeters are in one centimeter?',
  Option: ['10', '100', '1000', '10000'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 3,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'If a rectangle has a length of 8 cm and a width of 5 cm, what is its area?',
  Option: ['13 cm2', '30 cm2', '40 cm2', '48 cm2'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 4,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which unit is used to measure the volume of a liquid?',
  Option: ['Gram', 'Liter', 'Meter', 'Kilogram'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 5,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'What is the perimeter of a square with a side length of 6 meters?',
  Option: ['18 meters', '24 meters', '30 meters', '36 meters'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 6,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'How many grams are in one kilogram?',
  Option: ['100', '500', '1000', '1500'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 7,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'If a clock shows 3:45, how many degrees has the hour hand moved from 12:00?',
  Option: ['112.5°', '135°', '180°', '225°'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 8,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Which of the following is a unit of weight?',
  Option: ['Liter', 'Meter', 'Gram', 'Kilometer'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 9,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'If you travel 250 km in 5 hours, what is your average speed?',
  Option: ['45 km/h', '50 km/h', '55 km/h', '60 km/h'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 10,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 4,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'How many centimeters are in one meter?',
  Option: ['10', '100', '1000', '10000'],
  rightAns: 1
},

// subject Gujrati chapter 1 - Welcome
{
  queid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'What is the name of Kinjal\'s new friend?',
  Option: ['Sejal', 'Reva', 'Nisha', 'Diya'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 2,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'What game does Sejal invite Kinjal to play?',
  Option: ['Hide and Seek', 'Cricket', 'Kho-Kho', 'Kabaddi'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 3,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'How does Kinjal feel on the first day at the new school?',
  Option: ['Excited', 'Nervous', 'Sad', 'Angry'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 4,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Where does Kinjal sit in the classroom?',
  Option: ['Front row', 'Back row', 'Middle row', 'Next to Sejal'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 5,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'What gift does Kinjal give Sejal?',
  Option: ['Chocolates', 'Greeting card', 'Flowers', 'Toy'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 6,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'Where does Sejal take Kinjal during lunch break?',
  Option: ['Library', 'Playground', 'Canteen', 'Classroom'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 7,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'What food item does Kinjal share with Sejal?',
  Option: ['Sandwich', 'Pizza', 'Pasta', 'Burger'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 8,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'How does Kinjal travel to school?',
  Option: ['Bus', 'Car', 'Train', 'Auto rickshaw'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 9,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'What is Kinjal\'s father\'s name?',
  Option: ['Rajesh', 'Ramesh', 'Mahesh', 'Suresh'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 10,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'What is Kinjal\'s favorite subject?',
  Option: ['English', 'Maths', 'Science', 'Art'],
  rightAns: 2
},

// english ch - 1
{
  queid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'What is the meaning of the word \'stellar\'?',
  Option: ['Starry', 'Bright', 'Happy', 'Colorful'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 2,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which punctuation mark indicates a question?',
  Option: ['Exclamation point', 'Period', 'Question mark', 'Colon'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 3,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Choose the correct homophone for \'pear\':',
  Option: ['Pair', 'Peel', 'Peer', 'Pier'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 4,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which word means the opposite of \'brave\'?',
  Option: ['Cowardly', 'Kind', 'Joyful', 'Polite'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 5,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Choose the correct spelling of the word:',
  Option: ['Febuary', 'February', 'Februari', 'Feburary'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 6,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'Which word means the same as \'enormous\'?',
  Option: ['Tiny', 'Huge', 'Smooth', 'Dangerous'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 7,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Choose the correct synonym of \'jovial\':',
  Option: ['Gloomy', 'Merry', 'Boring', 'Lazy'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 8,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Which punctuation mark shows possession?',
  Option: ['Colon', 'Apostrophe', 'Quotation mark', 'Exclamation point'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 9,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Identify the common noun:',
  Option: ['Ring', 'Jenny', 'City', 'Sun'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 10,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Choose the correct article to fill in the blank: ____ apple a day keeps the doctor away.',
  Option: ['The', 'A', 'These', 'None'],
  rightAns: 1
},
// social science

{
  queid: 1,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'Who is known as the Iron Man of India?',
  Option: ['Jawaharlal Nehru', 'Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel', 'Lal Bahadur Shastri', 'Indira Gandhi'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 2,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which is the largest state in India by area?',
  Option: ['Maharashtra', 'Rajasthan', 'Madhya Pradesh', 'Uttar Pradesh'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 3,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Who wrote the Indian national anthem?',
  Option: ['Rabindranath Tagore', 'Bankim Chandra Chattopadhyay', 'Sarojini Naidu', 'Mohammad Iqbal'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 4,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which city is known as the Pink City of India?',
  Option: ['Jaipur', 'Jodhpur', 'Udaipur', 'Jaisalmer'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 5,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Which river is known as the Sorrow of Bengal?',
  Option: ['Ganga', 'Yamuna', 'Brahmaputra', 'Damodar'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 6,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'Where is the Victoria Memorial located?',
  Option: ['Mumbai', 'Chennai', 'Kolkata', 'Delhi'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 7,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Which is the largest ocean in the world?',
  Option: ['Atlantic Ocean', 'Indian Ocean', 'Arctic Ocean', 'Pacific Ocean'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 8,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Which planet is known as the Red Planet?',
  Option: ['Venus', 'Mars', 'Jupiter', 'Saturn'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 9,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Which vitamin helps our body fight infections?',
  Option: ['Vitamin A', 'Vitamin B', 'Vitamin C', 'Vitamin D'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 10,
  stdid: 1,
  subid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Who invented the light bulb?',
  Option: ['Thomas Edison', 'Albert Einstein', 'Isaac Newton', 'Marie Curie'],
  rightAns: 0
},
// std 6th subject maths
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'What is the smallest prime number ?',
  Option: ['0', '1', '2', '3'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which of the following is a composite number?',
  Option: ['11', '13', '9', '7'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'What is the value of the digit 5 in the number 8,549?',
  Option: ['5', '50', '500', '5000'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which Roman numeral represents the number 100?',
  Option: ['C', 'D', 'X', 'M'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 5,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'What is the sum of the first three prime numbers?',
  Option: ['6', '10', '11', '15'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 6,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'What is the product of 7 and 8?',
  Option: ['14', '56', '64', '15'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 7,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Which of the following is an odd number?',
  Option: ['20', '31', '42', '50'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 8,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'What is the place value of the digit 9 in the number 4,987?',
  Option: ['9', '90', '900', '9,000'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 9,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Which of the following is a multiple of 5?',
  Option: ['12', '15', '18', '21'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 10,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'If a number ends in 0, what is it always divisible by?',
  Option: ['2', '5', '10', '100'],
  rightAns: 2
},
// subject gujrati
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'Who is the author of the novel Saraswatichandra?',
  Option: ['Govardhanram Tripathi', 'K.M. Munshi', 'Ramanbhai Neelkanth', 'Dalpatram'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which of these is a pen name of Narmadashankar Dave?',
  Option: ['Narsinh', 'Kavi', 'Priya', 'Kamal'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Who wrote the novel Kadambari, considered the first Gujarati novel?',
  Option: ['Dalpatram', 'Narmadashankar Dave', 'Premanand Bhatt', 'Govardhanram Tripathi'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which of these is written by Premanand Bhatt?',
  Option: ['Sudamacharitra', 'Vasantvilas', 'Kusumamala', 'Hothalu Padmani'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 5,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Who wrote the poem Jai Jai Garavi Gujarat?',
  Option: ['Dalpatram', 'Narmadashankar Dave', 'Premanand Bhatt', 'Govardhanram Tripathi'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 6,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'Which of these is written by Ramanbhai Neelkanth?',
  Option: ['Prabhodhchandroday', 'Moolraj', 'Kusumamala', 'Veermati'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 7,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Who is the author of Batris Putli?',
  Option: ['Alexander Kinloch Forbes', 'Govardhanram Tripathi', 'Jhaverchand Meghani', 'K. M. Munshi'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 8,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Which literary work is authored by Dalpatram?',
  Option: ['Kavi Dalpatram ni Lekh Sangrah', 'Bhanakhar', 'Sudamacharitra', 'Veermati'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 9,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Who wrote the play Kanta?',
  Option: ['Umashankar Joshi', 'Sundaram', 'Govardhanram Tripathi', 'K. M. Munshi'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 10,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Which literary work is written by Narmadashankar Dave?',
  Option: ['Saraswatichandra', 'Veermati', 'Mari Hakikat', 'Sudamacharitra'],
  rightAns: 2
},
// english
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 1,
  question: "Choose the correct synonym of the word 'enormous':",
  Option: ['Tiny', 'Huge', 'Smooth', 'Dangerous'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which sentence has a spelling error?',
  Option: [
    'My mother made a deliscious cake.',
    'I want to become an ingineer.',
    'We went on a field trip to the zoo.',
    'That is an interseting story.'
  ],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Choose the correct abstract noun:',
  Option: ['Truth', 'Dog', 'Building', 'Box'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which punctuation mark shows possession?',
  Option: ['Colon', 'Apostrophe', 'Quotation mark', 'Exclamation point'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 5,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Choose the correct collective noun:',
  Option: ['Crowd', 'Team', 'Flock', 'Alphabet'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 6,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'Identify the common noun:',
  Option: ['Jupiter', 'Country', 'Ram', 'River'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 7,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Choose the correct antonym of the word \'brave\':',
  Option: ['Cowardly', 'Kind', 'Joyful', 'Polite'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 8,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Which punctuation mark begins and ends a quotation?',
  Option: ['Parentheses', 'Quotation marks', 'Apostrophe', 'Colon'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 9,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Choose the correct pronoun to fill in the blank: _______ is a doctor.',
  Option: ['She', 'They', 'It', 'Her'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 10,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Which literary work is written by Narmadashankar Dave?',
  Option: ['Saraswatichandra', 'Veermati', 'Mari Hakikat', 'Sudamacharitra'],
  rightAns: 2
},
// scoial science
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'Who invented the telephone?',
  Option: ['Thomas Edison', 'Alexander Graham Bell', 'Albert Einstein', 'Isaac Newton'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which planet is known as the Red Planet?',
  Option: ['Jupiter', 'Saturn', 'Mars', 'Venus'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Who discovered penicillin?',
  Option: ['Louis Pasteur', 'Alexander Fleming', 'Marie Curie', 'Albert Einstein'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which vitamin helps the body heal wounds?',
  Option: ['Vitamin A', 'Vitamin B', 'Vitamin C', 'Vitamin D'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 5,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Who proposed the three laws of motion?',
  Option: ['Albert Einstein', 'Isaac Newton', 'Marie Curie', 'Thomas Edison'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 6,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'What is the SI unit of force?',
  Option: ['Joule', 'Newton', 'Pascal', 'Watt'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 7,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Which gas forms the major part of the earth\'s atmosphere?',
  Option: ['Oxygen', 'Hydrogen', 'Nitrogen', 'Carbon dioxide'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 8,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Who invented the electric bulb?',
  Option: ['Marie Curie', 'Thomas Edison', 'Albert Einstein', 'Alexander Graham Bell'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 9,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Which planet is known as the Red Planet?',
  Option: ['Jupiter', 'Earth', 'Mars', 'Venus'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 10,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Who discovered gravity?',
  Option: ['Albert Einstein', 'Isaac Newton', 'Marie Curie', 'Thomas Edison'],
  rightAns: 1
},

// std 7th
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 2,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'What is the smallest prime number?',
  Option: ['0', '1', '2', '3'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which of the following is a composite number?',
  Option: ['11', '13', '9', '7'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'What is the value of the digit 5 in the number 8,549?',
  Option: ['5', '50', '500', '5000'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which Roman numeral represents the number 100?',
  Option: ['C', 'D', 'X', 'M'],
  rightAns: 'C'
},
{
  queid: 5,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'What is the sum of the first three prime numbers?',
  Option: ['6', '10', '11', '15'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 6,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'What is the product of 7 and 8?',
  Option: ['14', '56', '64', '15'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 7,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Which of the following is an odd number?',
  Option: ['20', '31', '42', '50'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 8,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'What is the place value of the digit 9 in the number 4,987?',
  Option: ['9', '90', '900', '9,000'],
  rightAns: 2
}, {
  queid: 9,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Which of the following is a multiple of 5?',
  Option: ['12', '15', '18', '21'],
  rightAns: 1
}, {
  queid: 10,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'If a number ends in 0, what is it always divisible by?',
  Option: ['2', '5', '10', '100'],
  rightAns: 2
},
// subject gujrati
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'Who is the author of the novel Saraswatichandra?',
  Option: [
    'Govardhanram Tripathi',
    'K.M. Munshi',
    'Ramanbhai Neelkanth',
    'Dalpatram'
  ],
  rightAns: 0 // Govardhanram Tripathi
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which of these is a pen name of Narmadashankar Dave?',
  option: [
    'Narsinh',
    'Kavi',
    'Priya',
    'Kamal'
  ],
  rightAns: 1 // Kavi
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Who wrote the novel Kadambar',
  Option: [
    'Dalpatram',
    'Narmadashankar Dave',
    'Premanand Bhatt',
    'Govardhanram Tripathi'
  ],
  rightAns: 1 // Narmadashankar Dave
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which of these is written by Premanand Bhatt?',
  Option: [
    'Sudamacharitra',
    'Vasantvilas',
    'Kusumamala',
    'Hothalu Padmani'
  ],
  rightAns: 1 // Vasantvilas
},
{
  queid: 5,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Who wrote the poem Jai Jai Garavi Gujarat?',
  Option: [
    'Dalpatram',
    'Narmadashankar Dave',
    'Premanand Bhatt',
    'Govardhanram Tripathi'
  ],
  rightAns: 1 // Narmadashankar Dave
},
{
  queid: 6,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'Which of these is written by Ramanbhai Neelkanth?',
  Option: [
    'Prabhodhchandroday',
    'Moolraj',
    'Kusumamala',
    'Veermati'
  ],
  rightAns: 2 // Veermati
},
{
  queid: 7,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Who is the author of Batris Putli?',
  Option: [
    'Alexander Kinloch Forbes',
    'Govardhanram Tripathi',
    'Jhaverchand Meghani',
    'K. M. Munshi'
  ],
  rightAns: 3 // Jhaverchand Meghani
},
{
  queid: 8,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Which literary work is authored by Dalpatram?',
  Option: [
    'Kavi Dalpatram ni Lekh Sangrah',
    'Bhanakhar',
    'Sudamacharitra',
    'Veermati'
  ],
  rightAns: 2 // Bhanakhar
},
{
  queid: 9,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Who wrote the play Kanta?',
  Option: [
    'Umashankar Joshi',
    'Sundaram',
    'Govardhanram Tripathi',
    'K. M. Munshi'
  ],
  rightAns: 2 // Sundaram
},
{
  queid: 10,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Which literary work is written by Narmadashankar Dave?',
  Option: [
    'Saraswatichandra',
    'Veermati',
    'Mari Hakikat',
    'Sudamacharitra'
  ],
  rightAns: 3 // Mari Hakikat
},
// english
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'Choose the correct synonym of the word \'enormous\':',
  Option: ['Tiny', 'Huge', 'Smooth', 'Dangerous'],
  rightAns: 1 // Huge
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which sentence has a spelling error?',
  Option: [
    'My mother made a deliscious cake.',
    'I want to become an ingineer.',
    'We went on a field trip to the zoo.',
    'That is an interseting story.'
  ],
  rightAns: 1 // 'I want to become an ingineer.'
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Choose the correct abstract noun:',
  Option: ['Truth', 'Dog', 'Building', 'Box'],
  rightAns: 0 // Truth
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which punctuation mark shows possession?',
  Option: ['Colon', 'Apostrophe', 'Quotation mark', 'Exclamation point'],
  rightAns: 1 // Apostrophe
},
{
  queid: 5,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Choose the correct collective noun:',
  Option: ['Crowd', 'Team', 'Flock', 'Alphabet'],
  rightAns: 2 // Flock
},
{
  queid: 6,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'Identify the common noun:',
  Option: ['Jupiter', 'Country', 'Ram', 'River'],
  rightAns: 3 // River
},
{
  queid: 7,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Choose the correct antonym of the word \'brave\':',
  Option: ['Cowardly', 'Kind', 'Joyful', 'Polite'],
  rightAns: 0 // Cowardly
},
{
  queid: 8,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Which punctuation mark begins and ends a quotation?',
  Option: ['Parentheses', 'Quotation marks', 'Apostrophe', 'Colon'],
  rightAns: 1 // Quotation marks
},
{
  queid: 9,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Choose the correct pronoun to fill in the blank: _______ is a doctor.',
  Option: ['She', 'They', 'It', 'Her'],
  rightAns: 0 // She
},
{
  queid: 10,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Identify the proper noun:',
  Option: ['Building', 'Delhi', 'Country', 'River'],
  rightAns: 1 // Delhi
},
// scoial science
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'Who invented the telephone?',
  Option: ['Thomas Edison', 'Alexander Graham Bell', 'Albert Einstein', 'Isaac Newton'],
  rightAns: 1 // Alexander Graham Bell
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which planet is known as the Red Planet?',
  Option: ['Jupiter', 'Saturn', 'Mars', 'Venus'],
  rightAns: 2 // Mars
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Who discovered penicillin?',
  Option: ['Louis Pasteur', 'Alexander Fleming', 'Marie Curie', 'Albert Einstein'],
  rightAns: 1 // Alexander Fleming
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Which vitamin helps the body heal wounds?',
  Option: ['Vitamin A', 'Vitamin B', 'Vitamin C', 'Vitamin D'],
  rightAns: 2 // Vitamin C
},
{
  queid: 5,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Who proposed the three laws of motion?',
  Option: ['Albert Einstein', 'Isaac Newton', 'Marie Curie', 'Thomas Edison'],
  rightAns: 1 // Isaac Newton
},
{
  queid: 6,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'What is the SI unit of force?',
  Option: ['Joule', 'Newton', 'Pascal', 'Watt'],
  rightAns: 1 // Newton
},
{
  queid: 7,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Which gas forms the major part of the earth\'s atmosphere?',
  Option: ['Oxygen', 'Hydrogen', 'Nitrogen', 'Carbon dioxide'],
  rightAns: 2 // Nitrogen
},
{
  queid: 8,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Who invented the electric bulb?',
  Option: ['Marie Curie', 'Thomas Edison', 'Albert Einstein', 'Alexander Graham Bell'],
  rightAns: 1 // Thomas Edison
},
{
  queid: 9,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Which planet is known as the Red Planet?',
  Option: ['Jupiter', 'Earth', 'Mars', 'Venus'],
  rightAns: 2 // Mars
},
{
  queid: 10,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 3,
  subid: 4,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Who discovered gravity?',
  Option: ['Albert Einstein', 'Isaac Newton', 'Marie Curie', 'Thomas Edison'],
  rightAns: 1 // Isaac Newton
},

// std 8th maths

// Maths
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'If A = {1, 2, 3} and B = {3, 4, 5}, what is A ∪ B?',
  Option: ['{1, 2, 3, 4, 5}', '{1, 2}', '{3, 4, 5}', '{1, 2, 3}'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'What is the HCF of 12, 18 and 30?',
  Option: ['2', '3', '6', '4'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'If a^2 - b^2 = 16 and ab = 8, what is the value of a + b?',
  Option: ['4', '8', '12', '16'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'The mean of the first 10 whole numbers is:',
  Option: ['5', '5.5', '10', '55'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 5,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'If 5x - 3(x + 2) = 7, then x equals:',
  Option: ['2', '5', '10', '-2'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 6,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'The perimeter of a rectangle is 140 cm. If its length is 30 cm, what is its breadth?',
  Option: ['20 cm', '35 cm', '55 cm', '105 cm'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 7,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Which decimal represents the fraction 5/4?',
  Option: ['0.2', '1.25', '1.5', '2.5'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 8,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'The simplest form of 0.4 is:',
  Option: ['2/5', '4/10', '8/20', '20/50'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 9,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'If 5a + 3b = 18 and 2a - b = 7, find a - b:',
  Option: ['2', '5', '6', '8'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 10,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 1,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'The least number which should be subtracted from 9320 to make it a perfect square is:',
  Option: ['3', '20', '80', '100'],
  rightAns: 3
},
// Gujarati
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'Who is the author of Batris Putli?',
  Option: ['Govardhanram Tripathi', 'K M Munshi', 'Jhaverchand Meghani', 'Ramanbhai Neelkanth'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which novel is written by Govardhanram Tripathi?',
  Option: ['Saraswatichandra', 'Snehrashmi', 'Vadhu Vidhati', 'Manvini Bhavai'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Who wrote the poem Jai Jai Garvi Gujarat?',
  Option: ['Narsinh Mehta', 'Premanand Bhatt', 'Narmadashankar Dave', 'Dalpatram'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Who wrote the novel Kadambari?',
  Option: ['Alexander Kinloch Forbes', 'Govardhanram Tripathi', 'Narmadashankar Dave', 'K M Munshi'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 5,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Who among the following was a social reformer?',
  Option: ['Gandhi', 'Dayanand Saraswati', 'Ranchhodlal Dave', 'Kavi Dalpatram'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 6,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'Who wrote the novel Snehrashmi?',
  Option: ['Ramanbhai Neelkanth', 'Pannalal Patel', 'Suresh Joshi', 'K M Munshi'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 7,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Who wrote the drama Jano Kharo Jani?',
  Option: ['Umashankar Joshi', 'Chinu Modi', 'Premanand Bhatt', 'Narsinh Mehta'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 8,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Who wrote the novel Bhadrambhadra?',
  Option: ['Joseph Macwan', 'Chandravadan Mehta', 'K M Munshi', 'Tarak Mehta'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 9,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Who wrote the collection Lekho?',
  Option: ['Sundaram', 'Govardhanram Tripathi', 'Kavi Dalpatram', 'Narmadashankar Dave'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 10,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 2,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Who wrote the play Kanta?',
  Option: ['Umashankar Joshi', 'Sundaram', 'Govardhanram Tripathi', 'K M Munshi'],
  rightAns: 1
},
// English
{
  queid: 1,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 1,
  question: 'Choose the word that is spelled correctly:',
  Option: ['Exaggerate', 'Exadurate', 'Egzaverate', 'Exajurate'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 2,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 2,
  question: 'Which of the following words is a noun?',
  Option: ['Run', 'Happy', 'Phone', 'Quickly'],
  rightAns: 2
},
{
  queid: 3,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 3,
  question: 'Choose the correct synonym of the word \'jovial\':',
  Option: ['Gloomy', 'Merry', 'Boring', 'Lazy'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 4,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 4,
  question: 'Choose the correct degree of the adjective \'wise\':',
  Option: ['Wisest', 'Most wise', 'More wise', 'Much wise'],
  rightAns: 0
},
{
  queid: 5,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 5,
  question: 'Identify the adverb in this sentence: She sang very beautifully.',
  Option: ['Sang', 'Beautifully', 'Very', 'She'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 6,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 6,
  question: 'Choose the correct collective noun:',
  Option: ['Furniture', 'Litter', 'Galaxy', 'Flock'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 7,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 7,
  question: 'Identify the abstract noun:',
  Option: ['Tree', 'Truth', 'Boy', 'Chair'],
  rightAns: 1
},
{
  queid: 8,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 8,
  question: 'Choose the correct preposition to fill in the blank: The cat hid ____ the sofa.',
  Option: ['Below', 'Above', 'Beside', 'Under'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 9,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 9,
  question: 'Choose the correct pronoun to complete the sentence: ____ went to the library.',
  Option: ['Him', 'They', 'It', 'She'],
  rightAns: 3
},
{
  queid: 10,
  chapterid: 1,
  stdid: 4,
  subid: 3,
  question_no: 10,
  question: 'Choose the correct homophone for \'hour\':',
  Option: ['Our', 'Are', 'Or', 'Oar'],
  rightAns: 0
}
]

module.exports = question
